Sachchidanand Shukla

Contact

1111 Block F, Sec 23-A Gurugram, Haryana 122017 +91-9870180080 sachchidanandshukla@live.com www.linkedin.com/in/snshukla/

sachchidanandshukla.in

Skills

Adaptability and Flexibility

Communication

Teamwork

Multi-tasking

Analytical Thinking

Technology Summary

Linux Administration

Virtualization Technology

Hands on Database Administration (oracle, postgre, MySQL)

Network Administration

Hands-on Oracle Cloud Infrastructure and AWS

VOIP/SIP, Asterisk

Active Directory Domain Services

Linux Server Hardening

Webserver Administration

Education

B. Tech - Computer Science (Shobhit University, 2009-13)

Profile

An excellent academic record, talented system administrator offering experience of 4 years in Unix/Linux environment and expertise in several flavors of Linux including Red Hat, CentOS, Ubuntu, Oracle Linux. Strong Grasp of computer security, assorted operating systems, numerous application, and mixed platforms.

Experience

Advology Solution Pvt Ltd• Gurugram

Linux System Administrator, 2016 to Present Technical Support Associate, 2014 to 2016

Promoted to system administrator role to lead a 10 member IT team in configuring, troubleshooting and maintaining Linux and Unix infrastructure for mid-sized digital marketing company.

- Performance Tuning: Ensure that assigned systems were engineered, configured and optimized for maximum functionality and availability. Implement solutions that reduced single point of failures and improve system uptime to 99.9% availability.
- **Management:** Proiect Lead Enterprise wide Hardware/Software installation: oversaw major server upgrade/expansion project that improved network access protection, terminal services, and network performance; and technologies existing integrate new into environments.
- Security: Closely work with in-house Network engineers to strengthen system/network security and business continuity planning as a member of company's security incident response team.
- Troubleshooting: Rectified many issues by instituting best practices in system log analysis, backups, network operating security, user account/permission management and system/software auditing.

April 2014— March 2016

- Deliver high-quality second-level service of the technology environment, manage service now incidents, provide desktop services and asset management.
- Manage work order resolution through first call resolution as per industry standards
- Complete effective work orders timely and efficiently to provide best troubleshooting results

Activities and Interests

Surfing, Reading, Cooking FIFA Mobile, PUBG

Cloud Computing, Software Defined Services

Achievements

- Configured filesharing server on Centos Linux integrating active directory authentication saving new hardware investments.
- IT Infrastructure setup for 150+ Employees.
- Implemented company-wide work from home network connectivity via Cisco AnyConnect VPN setup.

- Proactively communicate with customers, from analysis through resolution, to keep them informed of status; provide follow-up upon resolution to ensure customer satisfaction
- Provide intermediate-level network troubleshooting and services.
- Integration support for OS X and Windows.
- Provide ongoing support and communication to other staff members, promoting an empowered, multi-disciplinary team environment.
- Maintain effective communication with Team leaders, Service Desk teams, Vendors, manufacturers, and service providers.
- To be proactive in the avoidance of repetitive incidents through publishing "how to's and "tips" to users on a regular basis and ensuring that the knowledge base is kept up to date at all times.
- Provide ongoing support and communication to other staff members, promoting an empowered, multi-disciplinary team environment.
- Maintained composure and patience dealing with difficult costumer situations.

Additional Experience:

- Web hosting Panel Installation on VPS for hosting websites and other services e.g. cPanel, WHM, Webmin, CentOS Web Panel.
- Contact Centre Solution setup on VPS for IVR Broadcast and VOIP call termination and origination.
- Configuration of Online Backup Solution for VPS.
- Opensource Software defined storage setup for backup and filesharing.
- SMTP mail server configuration and DNS Setup for Effective delivery of bulk emails.